So, uh, hello everybody and welcome back to
Practical deep learning for coders. This is lesson two
and
and in the last lesson we
Started training our first models. We didn't really have any idea how that training was really working
But we were looking at a high-level at what was going on
and
We learned about
what is
Machine learning and how does that work?
and
We
realized that
Based on how machine learning worked that there are some fundamental limitations on on what it can do
And we've talked about some of those limitations now
We also talked about how after you've trained a machine learning model you end up with a program
which behaves much like a normal program or something with the inputs and a thing in the middle and
outputs
so today we're gonna
finish up talking about
Talking about that and we're going to then look at how we get those
Models into production and what some of the issues with doing that?
might be I
Wanted to remind you that there are
Two sets of books. I sorry two sets of notebooks available to you
One is the the the fast book
Repo the full actual notebooks containing all the text of the O'Reilly book
and so this lets you see
Everything that I'm telling you in much more detail
And then as well as that there's the course v4 repo which contains exactly the same notebooks
But with all the pros stripped away to help you study
so that's where you really want to be doing your experiment and your practice and so maybe as you
Listen to the video. You can kind of switch back and forth between the video and reading or do one and then the other
And then put it away and have a look at the course fee for notebooks and try to remember like okay
What was this section about and run the code and see what happens and change it and so forth
So we were looking at
This line of code where we looked at how we created
our our data
by passing in information, perhaps most importantly
Some way to label the data and we talked about the importance of labeling
And in this case this particular data set whether it's a cat or a dog
You can tell by whether it's an uppercase or a lowercase letter in the first
Position that's just how this data set if they tell you when the readme works
And we are also looked particularly at this idea of valid percent equals zero point two and like what does that mean?
It creates a validation set and that was something I wanted to talk more about
The first thing I do want to do though is point out that this particular
Labeling function returns something that's either true or false
And actually this data set as we'll see later also tells also contains the actual breed of
37 different cat and dog breeds so you can you can also grab that from the filename
In each of those two cases. We're trying to predict a category. Is it a cat or is it a dog or is it a
German Shepherd or a beagle or a ragdoll cat or whatever?
When you're trying to predict a category, so when the label is a category, we call that a classification model
on the other hand
You might try to predict. How old is the animal or how tall is it?
or
Something like that, which is like a continuous number that could be like 13.2 or 26.5 or whatever
Anytime you're trying to predict a number your label is a number you call that regression, okay?
So those are the two main types of model
Classification and regressions. This is very important. Jargon to know about so the regression model
Attempts to predict one or more numeric quantities such as temperature or location or whatever
this is a bit confusing because sometimes people use the word regression as a shortcut to a particular a like a
abbreviation for a particular kind of model called linear regression
That's super confusing because that's not what regression means linear regression is just a particular kind of regression
but I just wanted to warn you of that when you start talking about regression a lot of
People will assume you're talking about linear regression even though that's not what the word means
All right, so I wanted to talk about this valid percent zero point two thing, so as we described valid percent
grabs in this case twenty percent of the data if it's zero point two and puts it aside like in a separate bucket and
Then when you train your model
Your model doesn't get to look at that data at all
That data is only used to decide to show you how accurate your model is
So if you train for too long
And or with not enough data and/or a model with too many parameters
After a while the accuracy of your model will actually get worse and this is called overfitting
Right. So we use the validation set to ensure that we're not
overfitting the
Next line of code that we looked at is this one
where we created something called a learner we'll be learning a lot more about that that a learner is basically more is
something which contains your data and
your
Architecture that is the mathematical function that you're optimizing
And so a learner is the thing that tries to figure out what are the parameters which best cause this function?
To match the labels in this data
so we're talking a lot more about that, but basically
This particular function resinate 34 is the name of a particular architecture
Which is just very good for computer vision problems
in fact
The name really is ResNet and then 34 tells you how many layers there are so you can use ones with bigger numbers
Here to get more parameters that will take to train take more memory more likely to overfit that could also
Create more complex models
Right now though. I wanted to focus on this part here, which is metrics equals error rate
this is where you list the functions that you want to be the that you want to be called with your data with your
Validation data and print it out
after each epoch and
epoch is
is what we call it when you look at every single image in the data set once and
so after you've looked at every image in the data set once we print out some information about how you're doing and
The most important thing we print out is the result of calling these metrics
so error rate is the name of a metric and it's a function that just prints out what percent of the
Validation set are being incorrectly classified by your model
So our metrics a function that measures the quality of the predictions using the validation set
So error rates one another common metric is accuracy, which is just 1 minus error rate
So very important to remember from last week. We talked about loss
Arthur Samuel had this important idea in machine learning that we need some way to figure out how
Good our how well our model is doing so that when we change the parameters we can figure out which set of parameters make that
Performance measurement get better or worse
That performance measurement is called the loss
the loss is
Not necessarily the same as your metric
the reason why is a bit subtle and we'll be seeing it in a lot of detail once we delve into the math in the
coming lessons, but basically
You need a function. You need a loss function
Where if you change the parameters by just a little bit up or just a little bit down you can see if the loss gets
A little bit better or a little bit worse and it turns out that error rate and accuracy doesn't tell you that at all
Because you might change the parameters base much such a small amount
That none of your dog's predictions start becoming hats and none of your cat predictions start becoming dogs
So like your predictions don't change and your error rate doesn't change so
Loss and metric are closely related, but the metric is the thing that you care about
The loss is the thing which your computer is using as the measurement of performance to decide how to update your parameters
So we measure
Overfitting by looking at the metrics on the validation set so fast AI
always uses the validation set to print out your metrics and
Overfitting is like the key thing that machine learning is about it's all about. How do we find a model?
Which fits the data not just for the data that we're training with but for data that the training algorithm hasn't seen before
So
overfitting
results when
our model is basically
Cheating a model can cheat by saying
Oh
I've seen this exact picture before and I remember that that's a picture of a cat
So it might not have learnt what cats look like in general
It just remembers
you know that images one four and eight cats and two and three and five dogs and
Learns nothing actually about what they really look like. So that's the kind of cheating that we're trying to avoid
we don't want it to memorize our
particular data set
So we sped off our validation data
And what most of this are these words you're seeing on the screen are from the book. Okay, so I just copied and pasted them
so if we split off our validation data
And make sure that our model sees it during training. It's completely untainted by it so we can't possibly cheat
Not quite true we can cheat
The way we could cheat is we could run we could fit a model look at the result and the validation set
Change something a little bit fit another model
Look at the validation set change something a little bit we could do that like a hundred times
Until we find something with the validation set looks the best
But now we might have fit to the validation set
Right. So if you want to be really rigorous about this, you should actually set aside a third
Bit of data called the test set that is not used for training and it's not used for your metrics
It's actually you don't look at it until the Haab projects finished
And this is what's used on competition platforms like Kegel
on Kegel after the competition finishes
Your performance will be measured
Against a data set that you have never seen
and so
That's a really helpful
Approach and it's actually a great idea to do that. Like even if you're not doing the modeling yourself
so if you're
If you're looking at vendors
And you're just trying to decide today go with IBM or Google or Microsoft and they're all showing you how great their models are
What you should do is you should say okay you go and build your models
And I am going to hang on to 10% of my data and I'm not going to let you see it at all
And when you're all finished to come back and then I'll run your model on the tip as 10% of data. You've never seen
now
Pulling out your
Validation and test sets is a bit subtle, though
here's an example of a simple little data set and this comes from a
Fantastic blog post that Rachel wrote that we will link to about creating effective validation sets
And you can see basically you have some kind of seasonal data set here. Now if you just say
okay, first day I want to model that I want to create a
My data loader using a valid percent of 0.2
It would do this. It would delete randomly some of the dots
right now
This isn't very helpful
Because it's we can still cheat because these dots are right in the middle of other dots
And this isn't what would happen in practice?
What would happen in practice is we would want to predict this is sales by date, right?
We want to predict the sales for next week. Not the sales for
14 days ago 18 days ago and 29 days ago, okay
So what you actually need to do to create an effective validation set here is not do it randomly. But instead
chop off
the end
Right. And so this is what happens in all kaggle competitions pretty much that involve time for instance is the thing that you have to
Predict is the next like two weeks or so after the last data point that they give you
And this is what you should do also for your test set
So again, if you've got vendors that you're looking at you should say to them
Okay, after you're all done modeling, we're going to check your model against a data
that is one week later than you've ever seen before and
You won't be able to retrain or anything because that's what happens in practice, right?
Oops, there's a question. I've heard people describe
Overfitting as training error being below validation error. Does this rule of thumb end up being roughly the same as yours?
Okay, so that's a great question
So I think what they mean, there is training loss versus validation loss
Because we don't print training error
so we do print at the end of each epoch the value of your loss function for the training set and the value of the
loss function for the validation set and
If you train for long enough that's so so if it's training mostly
Your training loss will go down and your validation loss will go down
because by definition
Loss function is to find such as a lower loss function is a better model
if you start overfitting
Your training loss will keep going down. Right because like why wouldn't it, you know, you're getting better and better parameters
But your validation loss will start to go up
Because actually you started fitting to the specific data points in the training set. And so it's not going to actually get better
It's going to get it's not going to get better for the validation set. It'll start to get worse
however
That does not
Necessarily mean that you're overfitting or at least not overfitting in a bad way as we'll see
It's actually possible to be at a point where the validation
Loss is getting worse but the validation accuracy or error or metric is still improving
So I'm not going to describe
How that would happen mathematically yet because we need to learn more about loss functions
But we will but for now just realize that the important thing to look at is your metric
Getting worse not your loss function getting worse
Thank you for that. Fantastic question
The next important thing we need to learn about is called transfer learning. So the next line of code said learned fine tuned
Why does it say learn dot fine to?
Fine tune is what we do when we are
Transfer learning so transfer learning is using a pre trained model for a task that is different to what it was originally trained for
So more. Jargon to understand our jargon, let's look at that. What's a pre trained model? So what happens is remember?
I told you the architecture we're using is called resonate 34
So when we take that resonate 34, that's just a just a mathematical function
Okay with lots of parameters that we're going to fit using machine learning
There's a big data set called imagenet that contains 1.3 million pictures of a thousand different types of thing
Mushrooms or animals or aeroplanes or hammers or whatever?
There's a competition or they used to be a competition that runs every year to see who could get the best
Accuracy on the imagenet competition and the models that did really well
people would take
Those specific values of those parameters and they would make them available on the internet for anybody to download
So if you download that you don't just have an architecture now you have a trained model
You have a model that can recognize a thousand
categories of thing in images
Which probably isn't very useful unless you happen to want something that recognizes those exact thousand categories of thing
But it turns out you can
Rather you can with those weights in your model and then train some more epochs
On your data and you'll end up with a far far more
Accurate model than you would if you didn't start with that pre train model and we'll see why in just a moment, right?
But this idea of transfer learning it's kind of it makes intuitive sense, right?
Imagenet already has some cats and some dogs and it's you know
It can say this is a cat and this is a dog
But you want to maybe do something that recognizes lots of breeds that aren't an image net
Well for it to be able to recognize cats versus dogs versus airplanes versus hammers. It has to understand things like
What does metal look like what is fur look like what it is look like you know so it can say like oh this breed
Of animal this breed of dog has pointy ears and oh this thing is metal. So it can't be a dog
So all these kinds of concepts get implicitly learned by a pre trained model
So if you start with a pre trained model, then you don't it. You don't have to learn all these features
from scratch and so transfer learning is the
Single most important thing for being able to use less data and less compute and get better accuracy
So that's a key focus for the FASTA eye library and a key focus for this course
There's a question and I am a bit confused on the differences between loss error and metric
Sure, so
Era is just one
Kind of metric. So there's lots of different possible labels. You could have let's say you are trying to create a model
which could predict how old a
cat or dog is
so
The metric you might use is on average how many years were you off by?
So that would be a metric on the other hand if you're trying to predict whether this is a cat or a dog
Your metric would be
What percentage of the time am I wrong?
So that latter metric is called the error rate. Okay, so error is one particular metric. It's a thing that measures
How well you're doing and it's like it should be the thing that you most care about
So you you write a function or use one of fast a i's predefined ones
Which measures how well you're doing?
Loss
Is the thing that we talked about in Lesson one, so I'll give a quick summary
But go back to lesson one if you don't remember
Arthur Samuel talked about how a machine learning model needs some measure of performance
Which we can look at when we adjust our parameters our pour down. Does that measure of performance get better or worse and
as I mentioned earlier
Some metrics
Possibly won't change at all if you move the parameters up and down just a little bit so they can't be used
For this purpose of adjusting the parameters to find a better measure of performance. So quite often
We need to use a different function
we call this the loss function and
the loss function is the measure of performance that the algorithm uses to try to make the parameters better and
It's something which should kind of track pretty closely to the the metric you care about
But it's something which as you change the parameters a bit the loss should always change a bit
and so
There's a lot of hand waving there
Because we need to look at some of the math of how that works and we'll be doing that in the next couple of lessons
Thanks to their great questions
Okay, so fine tuning is a particular transfer learning technique where the
When you're still showing your picture and not the slides
So fine-tuning is a transfer learning technique where the weights this is not quite the right word
We should say the parameters where the parameters of a pre-trained model are updated by training for additional epochs
Using a different task to that used for pre training
So pre training the tasks that have been imaged met classification and then our different tasks might be recognizing cats versus dogs
So the way
By default fast AI does fine tuning is that we use one epoch, which remember is one
looking at every image in the data set once one epoch to fit just those parts of the model necessary to
Get the particular part of the model. That's
Especially for your data set working
And then we use
as many epochs as you asked for to fit the whole model and
So this is more if you for those people who might be a bit more advanced
We'll see exactly how this works later on in the lessons
So why does transfer learning work and why does it work? So well?
the best way in my opinion to look at this is to see this paper by Zeiler and furgus who were actually
2012 imagenet winners and
interestingly
Their key insights came from their ability to visualize what's going on inside a model and so our visualization
Very often turns out to be super important to getting great results
What they were able to do was they looked remember I told you like a resinate 34 has 34 layers
They looked at
Something called Alec's net which was the previous winner of the competition, which only had seven layers at the time that was considered huge
And so they took the seven layer model and they said what is the first layer of?
Parameters look like and they figured it out how to draw a picture of them, right?
and so the first layer had
Lots and lots of features but here are nine of them. One, two, three, four, five six, seven eight nine and
Here's what nine of those pictures look like
One of them was something that could recognize diagonal lines from top left to bottom
right
One of them could find diagonal lines from bottom left to top right?
one of them could find gradients that went from the top of orange to the bottom of
Blue some of them were able, you know, one of them was specifically for finding things that were green
And so forth right so for each of these nine
They're called filters there are features
So then something really interesting they did was they looked at for each one of these
Each one of these filters each one of these features and we'll learn kind of mathematically about what these actually mean
In the coming lessons, but for now
Let's just recognize them and saying oh there's something that looks at diagonal lines and something that looks at gradients
And they found in the actual images in imagenet
Specific examples of parts of photos that match that filter so for this top left filter here are nine
actual patches of real photos that match that filter and as you can see
They're all diagonal lines. And so here's the four the green one. Here's parts of actual photos that match the green one
So layer one is super super simple. And one of the interesting things to note here. Is that something that can recognize?
Gradients and patches of color and lines is likely to be useful for lots of other tasks as well
Not just imagenet so you can kind of see how something that can do this
might also be good at
Many many other computer vision tasks as well
This is layer 2 layer
2 takes the features of layer 1 and combines them
so it can not just find edges that can find corners or
Repeating curving patterns or semi circles or full circles. And so you can see for example, here's a
It's kind of hard to exactly visualize these
Layers after layer 1 you kind of have to show examples of what the filters look like
but here you can see examples of parts of photos that these this layer 2 circular filter has
activated on
And as you can see, it's found things with circles
so interestingly this one which is this kind of blotchy gradient seems to be very good at finding sunsets and
this repeating vertical pattern is very good at finding like curtains and wheat
fields and stuff
So the further we get layer three then gets to combine all the kinds of features in layer
Two and remember, we're only seeing Zoar anything here are twelve of the features, but actually there's probably hundreds of them
I don't remember exactly an alux net, but there's lots
But by the time we get to layer three by combining features from layer two, it already has something which is finding
Text so this is a feature which can find bits of image that contain text
It's already got something which can find
repeating geometric patterns and you see this is not just like a
Matching specific pixel patterns. This is like a
Semantic concept it can find repeating circles or repeating squares or repeating hexagons
Great, so it's it's really like computing. It's not just
Matching a template and remember we know that neural networks can solve any possible computable function so it can certainly do that
So layer four gets to combine
All the filters from layer three anyway at once and so by layer four, we have something that can find dog faces
for instance
so you can kind of see how
Each layer, we get like more applicative lis more sophisticated features
And so that's why these deep neural networks can be so incredibly powerful
It's also why transfer learning can work so well because like if we wanted something that can find
Books, and I don't think there's a book category in imagenet
Well, it's actually already got something that can find text as an earlier filter, which I guess it must be using to find
Maybe there's a category for library or something or a bookshelf
So when you use transfer learning you can take advantage of all of these pre I learnt
Features to find things that are as combinations of these or existing features
That's why transfer learning can be done so much more quickly and so much less data than traditional approaches
One important thing to realize then is that these techniques for computer vision are not just good at
recognizing photos
There's all kinds of things you can turn into pictures. For example, these are example these are
sounds that have been tuned into pictures by representing their frequencies over time and
It turns out that if you convert a sound into these kinds of pictures
You can get basically state-of-the-art results at sound detection
Just by using the exact same resonate
learner that we've already seen
We need to highlight that it's 945. So if you want to take a break soon
a really cool example
From I think this is our very first year of running fast AI one of our students
Created pictures they worked at Splunk in anti-fraud and they created pictures of users moving their mouths
And if I remember correctly as they moved their mouths
He basically drew a picture of where the mouse moved and the color depended on how fast they moved and these
circular blobs is where they clicked the left or the right mouse button and
It's blank. They then well, he what he did actually for the through the course as a
Project for the course is he tried to see whether he could use this these pictures with exactly the same approach?
We saw in lesson 1 to create an anti fraud model and it worked
So well that Splunk ended up patenting a new product based on this technique and you can actually check it out
there's a blog post about it on the internet where they describe this breakthrough anti-fraud approach which literally came from
One of our really amazing and brilliant and creative students after lesson one of the course
Another cool example of this is looking at different
viruses and
Again, turning them into pictures and you can kind of see how they've got here. This is from a paper
Check out the book for the citation
they've got three examples of a particular virus called VB 80 and another
example of a particular virus called fake rien and you can see each case the pictures all look kind of similar and
That's why again
they can get state-of-the-art results in in virus detection by turning the
Kind of program signatures into pictures and putting it through image recognition
So in the book you'll find a list of all of the terms all of the most important terms
We've seen both so far and what they mean. I'm not going to read through them
but I want you to please because these are the these are the terms that we're going to be using from now on and
You've got to know what they mean
because if you don't you're going to be really confused because I'll be talking about labels and architectures and models and parameters and
They have very specific exact meanings and they'll be using those exact meanings. So please review this
So to remind you this is where we got to we we ended up with Arthur Samuels overall
Approach and we replaced his terms with our terms. So we have an architecture
Which contains parameters as inputs and we more parameters and the data as inputs?
So that the architecture press the parameters of the model
With the inputs they used to calculate predictions
They are compared to the labels with a loss function and that loss function is used to update the parameters
Many many times to make them better and better until the loss gets nice and super low
So this is the end of chapter 1 of the book
it's really important to look at the questionnaire because the questionnaire is the thing where you can check whether you
Have taken away from this book of this chapter the stuff that we hope you have so go through it and
Anything that you're not sure about the tech that the answer is in the text
So just go back to earlier in the book and you will in the chapter and you will find the answers
There's also a further research section after each questionnaire for the first couple of chapters, they're actually pretty simple
Hopefully they're pretty fun and interesting. They're things were to answer the question. It's not enough to just look in the chapter
You actually have to go and do your own thinking and experimenting and googling and so forth
In later chapters, some of these further research things are pretty significant projects that might take a few days or even weeks
and so
yeah, you know check them out because hopefully they'll be a great way to
Expand your understanding of the material
So something that still found points out in the book is that if you really want to make the most of this
then after each chapter
Please take the time to experiment with your own project and within the books you provide we provide and then see if you can
Redo the the notebooks on a new data set and perhaps for chapter one
That might be a bit hard because we haven't really shown how to change things but for chapter four chapter two
Which we're going to start next you'll absolutely be able to do that
Okay, so let's take a break and we'll come back at 9:55
San Francisco time
Okay, so welcome back everybody and I think we've got a couple of questions to start with. So Rachel, please take it away. Sure
Our filters independent by that
I mean if filters are pre-trained might they become less good and detecting features of previous images when fine-tuned. Oh
That is a great question
So assuming I understand the question correctly if if you start with say an image NIT model and then you you fine-tune it on
Dogs versus cats for a few epochs and you get something that's very good at recognizing dogs versus cats
It's got to be much less good as an image net model after that
So it's not going to be very good at recognizing aeroplanes or or hammers or whatever
This is called catastrophic
Forgetting in the literature the idea that as you like see more images
About different things to what you saw earlier that you start to forget what the things you saw earlier?
So if you want to fine-tune something which is
Good at a new task but also continues to be good at the previous task
You need to keep putting in examples of the previous task as well
And what are the example what are the differences between parameters and hyper parameters
If I am feeding an image of a dog as an input and then changing the hyper parameters of batch size and the model
What would be an example of a parameter?
So the parameters are the things that
are described in lesson one that Arthur Samuel described as being
The things which change
What the model does what the architecture does so we start with this infinitely flexible function
The thing called a neural network that can do anything at all
and
the
The way you get it to do one thing versus another thing is by changing its parameters. They're there
They are the numbers that you pass into that function. So there's two types of numbers you pass into the function
There's the numbers that represent your input like the pixels of your dog. And there's the numbers that represent
Their learnt parameters
So in the example of something that's not a neural net but like a checkers playing program
Like Arthur Samuel might have used back in the early 60s and late 50s. Those parameters may have been things like
if there is a
Opportunity to take a piece versus an opportunity to get to the end of a board
How much more value should I consider one versus the other?
You know, it's twice as important or it's three times as important that two versus three, that would be an example of a parameter
In a
neural network
Parameters are a much more abstract concept and so a detailed understanding of what they are will come in the next lesson or two
But it's the same basic idea there the numbers which change
What the model does to be something that recognizes?
malignant tumors versus cats versus dogs versus colorizer splack and white pictures
Whereas the hyper parameter is
the choices about
What?
What numbers do you pass to the function when you act the actual fitting function to decide how that fitting process happens?
it
There's a question. I'm curious about the pacing of this course. I'm concerned that all the material may not be covered
It depends what you mean by all the material we certainly won't cover everything in the world
So yeah
We'll cover what we can well cover what we can in seven lessons
We're certainly not covering the whole book if that's what you're wondering. The whole book will be covered in either two or three courses
In the past. It's generally been two courses to cover about the amount of stuff in the book
But we'll see how it goes because the books pretty big 500 pages
So when you say two courses you mean fourteen lesson 14
Yes, it would be like 14 or 21 lessons to get through the whole book
Well, though having said that by the end of the first lesson
Hopefully there'll be kind of like enough momentum and understanding that the reading the book independently will be more
useful and you'll have also kind of
Gained a community of folks on the forums that you can hang out with and ask questions of and so forth
So in in the second part of the course, we're going to be talking about putting stuff in production and
We're so to do that we need to understand like what are the capabilities and limitations of
Deep learning what are the kinds of?
projects that even makes sense to try to put in production
And you know one of the key things I should mention in the book and in this core
Is that the first two or three lessons and chapters?
there's a lot of stuff which is designed not just for
the coders but for for everybody there's lots of information about like
What are the practical things you need to know to make deep learning work?
And so one of them things you need to know is like well what's deep learning actually good at at the moment
So I'll summarize what the book says about this but
there are the kind of four key areas that we
Have as applications in faster a computer vision text
Tabular and what I've called here XE assistance for recommendation systems and specifically a technique called collaborative filtering which we briefly saw
Sorry, another question and is are there any pre trained weights available other than the ones from imagenet that we can use if?
Yes, when should we use others in one imagenet? Oh, that's a really great question
so
yes, there are a lot of pre trained models and
One way to find them. But also you're currently just showing us what you can great
Now one great way to find them is you can look up
Models ooh
Which is a common name for like places that have lots of different models
And so here's lots of models is or you can look for
Pre-trained models
And so yeah, there's quite a few um, unfortunately
Not as wide a variety as I would like that most is still on image net or similar kinds of general photos
for example medical imaging there's hardly any
There's a lot of opportunities for people to create domain-specific pre-trained models, it's it's still an area
That's really underdone because not enough people are working on transfer learning
Okay, so as I was mentioning we've kind of got these four applications that we've talked about a bit
And deep learning is pretty, you know, pretty good at all of those
Tabular data like spreadsheets and database tables is an area where dick learning is not always the best choice
But it's particularly good for things involving high cardinality variables
that means variables that have like lots and lots of discrete levels like zip code or
Product ID or something like that
deep loadings really pretty great for those in particular
For text it's pretty great at things like classification and translation
It's actually terrible for conversation. And so that's that's been something that's been a huge disappointment for a lot of companies
I tried to create these like conversation BOTS
but actually deep learning isn't good at
providing accurate information
it's good at providing things that sound accurate and sound compelling but
That we don't really have great ways yet of actually making sure it's correct
One big issue for recommendation systems collaborative filtering is that
Deep learning is focused on making predictions
Which don't necessarily actually mean creating useful recommendations. We'll see what that means in a moment
Deep learning is also good at multimodal
That means things where you've got
Multiple different types of data so you might have some tabular data including a text column and an image
Then some collaborative filtering data
And combining that all together is something that deep learning is really good at
so for example
Putting captions on photos is something which deep learning is pretty good at although again
It's not very good at being accurate
So what you know might say this is a picture of two birds when it's actually a picture of three birds
And then this other category
there's
Lots and lots of things that you can do with deep learning by being creative about the use of these kinds of other
Application based approaches for example an approach that we developed for natural language processing called you LM fit
They're all you're learning in the course
It turns out that it's also fantastic you're doing protein analysis. If you think of the different proteins as being different words
And they're in a sequence which has some kind of state and meaning
It turns out that you will M fit works really well for protein analysis so often it's about kind of being being creative
So to decide like for the product that you're trying to build is deep learning gonna work
Well for it in the end you kind of just have to try it and see
But if you if you do a search, you know, hopefully you can find examples about the people that have tried something similar
Even if you can't that doesn't mean it's not going to work
So, for example, I mentioned the collaborative filtering issue where a recommendation and a prediction are not necessarily the same thing
You can see this on
Amazon for example quite often so I bought a terry pratchet book and
Then Amazon tried for months to get me to buy more terry pratchet books
now that must be because their predictive model said that people who bought one particular terry patcher book are likely to also by
other terry pratchet books
But from the point of view of like well is this going to change my buying behavior?
Probably not right like if I liked that book
I already know I like that author and I already know that like they probably wrote other things
So I'll go and buy it anyway, so this would be an example of like Amazon
Probably not being very smart up here. They're actually showing me
Collaborative filtering predictions rather than actually figuring out how to optimize a recommendation
So an optimized recommendation would be something more like your local
Human bookseller might do where they might say. Oh you like Terry Pratchett
Well, let me tell you about other kind of comedy fantasy sci-fi writers on the similar vein who you might not have heard about before
So the difference between recommendations and predictions is super important
so I wanted to talk about a really important issue around interpreting models and
For a case study for this I thought we let's pick something that's actually super important right now
Which is a model in this paper?
One of the things we're going to try and do in this course is learn how to read papers
So here is a paper, which you I would love for everybody to read
Called high temperature and high humidity reduce the transmission of kovat 19. Now. This is a very important issue
Because if the claim of this paper is true
then that would mean that this is going to be a
Seasonal disease and if this is a seasonal disease and it's going to have massive policy implications
So, let's try and find out how this was modeled and understand how to interpret this model
So, this is a
Key picture from the paper and what they've done here is they've
taken a hundred cities in China and they've plotted the temperature on one axis in
Celsius and are on the other axis where R is a measure of transmissibility. It says for each person that has this
disease
How many people on average will they?
infect so if R is under 1 then the disease will not spread is over R is
Higher than like 2 it's going to spread incredibly quickly
And basically R is going to you know, any high R is going to create an exponential transmission impact
And you can see in this case. They have plotted a best fit line
through here
Them and then they've made a claim that there's some particular
Relationship in terms of a formula that R is one point nine nine minus 0.02 three times temperature
so
very obvious concern I would have looking at this picture is that
This might just be random maybe there's no relationship at all, but just if you picked a hundred
Cities at random perhaps they were sometimes show this level of relationship
So one simple way to kind of see that would be to actually do it in a spreadsheet
so
Yes, here is a spreadsheet where what I did was I kind of eyeballed this data and I guessed about what is the main?
Degrees centigrade I think it's about five and what's about the standard deviation of centigrade? I think it's probably about five as well
and then I did the same thing for our I think I mean our looks like it's about
1.9 to me and it looks like the standard deviation of R is probably about 0.5
So what I then did was I just jumped over here and I created a
random
Normal value so a random value from a normal distribution from a normal distribution
So a bell curve with that particular mean and standard deviation of temperature and that particular
Mean and standard deviation of R. And so this would be an example of
a city that
Might be in this data set of a hundred cities something with nine degrees Celsius and an hour of 1.1
So that would be nine degrees Celsius and an hour of 1.1. So something about here
And so then I just copied that formula down
100 times
So here are a hundred cities
that could be in China right where this is assuming that there is no relationship between
temperature and R right there just random numbers
and
So each time I recalculate that so if I hit control equals it will just recalculate it
Right I get different numbers
Okay, because they're random and so you can see at the top here
I've then got the average of
All of the temperatures and the average of all of the hours and the average of all the temperatures
Varies and the average of all of the odds varies as well. So then I
What I did was I copied those random numbers
Over here
Let's actually do it so I'll go copy these 100 random numbers and paste them
Here
Here here here. And so now I've got
1 2 3 4 5 6 I've got 6 kind of groups of 100 cities
all right, and so let's
Stop those from randomly changing any more by just fixing them in stone there
Okay, so now that I've pasted them in I've got
6 examples of what a hundred cities might look like if there was no relationship at all between temperature and R and
I've got their mean temperature and R in each of those six examples
And what I've done is you can see here at least for the first one is I've plotted it
Right and you can see in this case. There's actually a
slight positive slope and
I've actually calculated
The slope
For each just by using the slope function in Microsoft Excel and you can see that actually
In this particular case is just random
Five times it's been
Negative and it's even more negative than their
0.023
And so you can like it's kind of matching our intuition here
which is that this the slope of the line that we have here is
Something that absolutely can often happen totally by chance. It doesn't seem to be indicating any kind of real relationship at all
if we wanted that slope to be like
More confident we would need to look at more cities. So like here I've got
3,000 randomly generated numbers and you can see here. The slope is
0.0002 right. It's almost exactly zero, which is what we'd expect right when there's actually no relationship between C and R
And in this case there isn't they're all random
Then if we look at lots and lots of randomly generated cities, then we can say oh, yeah, there's there's no slope
But when you only look at a hundred as we did here you're going to see relationships
Totally coincidentally very very often. All right, so that's something that we need to be able to measure and
So one way to measure that is we use something called a p-value
So a p-value here's our p-value works
we start out with something called a null hypothesis and the null hypothesis is basically what's what's our
starting point assumption so our starting point assumption might be oh
There's no relationship between temperature and R. And then we gather some data and have you explained what R is I have. Yes
How is the transmissibility of the virus?
So then we gather data of independent and dependent variables, so in this case the independent variable is the thing that we think
Might cause the dependent variable. So here the independent variable would be temperature the dependent variable would be R. So here we've gathered data
There's the data that was gathered in this example
And then we say what does centage of the time would we see this amount of relationship?
which is a slope of 0.02 3 by chance and
as we've seen one way to do that is by what we would call a
simulation which is by generating random numbers 100 set pairs of random numbers a bunch of times and seeing how often
You see this this relationship?
We don't actually have to do it that though, there's actually a
Simple equation we can use to jump straight to this number which is what percent of the time would we see that relationship by chance?
And
This is basically what that looks like we have the
Most likely observation which in this case would be if there is no relationship between temperature
then the most likely slope would be zero and
sometimes you get positive slopes by chance and sometimes you get
pretty small slopes and sometimes you get
large negative slopes by chance and so
the you know
the larger the number the less likely it is to happen whether it be on the positive side or the negative side and
so in our case our question was
How often are we going to get less than negative 0.02 3 so it would actually be somewhere down here
And I actually copy this from Wikipedia where they were looking for positive numbers
And so they've colored in this area above the number
So this is the p-value and so you can we don't care about the math, but there's a simple little equation you can use to
directly figure out
This number the p-value from the data
So this is kind of how nearly all
kind of medical research results tend to be shown and
Folks really focus on this idea of p-values and indeed in this particular study
As well see in a moment. They reported p-values
So probably a lot of you have seen p-values in your previous lives. They come up in a lot of different domains
Here's the thing
They are terrible you almost always shouldn't be using them
Don't just trust me trust the American Statistical Association
They point out six things about p-values
And those include p-values do not measure the probability that the hypothesis is true
Or the probability that the data were produced by random choice alone
now we know this because we just saw that if we use more data, right so if we sample
Three thousand random cities rather than 100 we get a much
Smaller value, right? So p-values don't just tell you about how big a relationship is
But they actually tell you about a combination of that and how much data did you collect? All right, so
So they don't measure the probability. The hypothesis is true. So therefore
Conclusions and policy decisions should not be based on whether a p-value passes some threshold
P-value does not measure
the importance of a result
Right because again, it could just tell you that you collected lots of data
Which doesn't tell you that the results actually of any practical import and so by itself. It does not provide a good measure of evidence
So Frank Harrell who is somebody who I read his book and it's a really important part of my learning
He's a professor of biostatistics has a number of great articles about this
He says
Null hypothesis, testing and p-values have done significant harm to science
And he wrote another piece called and the whole hypothesis significance testing never worked
so
I've shown you what?
p-values are so that you know why they don't work not so that you can use them right, but they're a super important part of
machine learning because they come up all the time in making just you know, when people saying this is how we decide whether
your drug worked or whether there is a
Epidemiological relationship or whatever and indeed
p-values appear in this paper
so in the paper, they show the results of a
multiple linear regression
And they put three stars next to any
Relationship which has a p-value of 0.01 or less?
So
There is something useful to say about a small p-value like 0.01 or less
Which is the thing that we're looking at did not probably did not happen by chance
right the biggest
statistical error people make all the time is that they see that a p-value is not less than
0.05 and then they make the erroneous
conclusion that no
relationship exists, right
Which doesn't make any sense because like let's say you only had like three data points
Then you almost certainly won't have enough data to have a p-value of less than 0.05 for any
Hypothesis, so like the way to check is to go back and say what if I picked the exact opposite null hypothesis
What if my null hypothesis was there is a relationship between temperature and R
Then do I have enough data to?
Reject that null hypothesis. All right, and if the answer is no
then
You just don't have enough data to make any conclusions at all. All right
so in this case, they do have enough data to be confident that there is a relationship between
temperature and ah
Now, that's weird
because we just looked at the graph and we did a little back of a bit of a back-of-the-envelope in Excel and we thought
This is could it could well be random so
Here's where the issue is
the graph shows what we call a univariate relationship a univariate relationship shows the relationship between
One independent variable and one dependent variable and that's what you can normally show on a graph
but in this case they did a
multivariate model in which they looked at temperature and
humidity and
GDP per capita and
population density
And when you put all of those things into the model, then you end up with statistically significant results for temperature and humidity
Why does that happen? Well, the reason that happens is because
All these variation in the blue dots is not random
There's a reason they're different right and the reasons include
denser cities are going to have higher transmission for instance and
Probably more humid who have less transmission. So when you do a
Multivariate model, it actually allows you to be more confident of your results, right?
But the p-value as noted by the American Statistical Association does not tell us whether this is a practical importance
The thing that tells us is this is practical as importance is the actual slope
That's found and so in this case
The equation they come up with is that R equals three point nine six eight minus three point
Oh point O three eight by temperature minus point zero two four by relative humidity
This is this equation is this practically important? Well, we can again do a little back of the envelope here
By just putting that into
Excel let's say there was one place. It had a temperature of ten centigrade and a humidity of forty then if this equation is
Correct, R would be about two point seven
Somewhere with the temperature of 35 centigrade and a humidity of eighty
Will be about point eight
So is this practically important? Oh my god. Yes, right
two different cities with different climates
Can be if they're the same in every other way and this model is correct
Then one city would have no spread of disease because R is less than 1 1 would have massive exponential explosion
so
We can see from this model that if the modeling is correct, then this is a highly practically significant result
So this is how you determine practical significance of your models is not with p-values
But with looking at kind of actual outcomes
So, how do you think about?
the practical importance
Of a model and how do you turn a predictive model into something useful in production?
so I spent many many years thinking about this and I actually
created a
With some other great folks actually created a paper about it
Designing great data products
And
This is largely based on
Ten years of work I did at a company
I founded called optimal decisions group and optimal decisions group was
focused on a question of helping insurance companies what prices to set
and
Insurance companies up until that point had focused on predictive modeling actuaries in particular
Spent their time trying to figure out
How likely is it that you're going to crash your car and if you do how much damage might you have?
And then based on that try to figure out what price they should set for your policy
So for this company what we did was we decided to use a different approach
Which I ended up calling the drivetrain approach which is described here
to
Just set insurance prices and indeed to do all kinds of other things and so for the Insurance example
the objective would be if an insurance company would be
how do I maximize my
let's say five-year profit and
Then what inputs can we control? Can we control which what I call levers?
so in this case, it would be what price can I set and
Then data is data, which can tell you as you change your levers. How does that change your objective?
So if I start increasing my price to people who are likely to crash their car, then will get less of them
Which means we have less costs, but at the same time we'll also have less revenue coming in. For example
So to link up there kind of the levers to the objective via the data, we collect we build models that described how the levers
influence objective and this is all like
It seems pretty obvious. What do you say it like this, but when we started work with
Optimal decisions in 1999. Nobody was doing this an insurance everybody in insurance was simply doing a predictive model
To guess how likely people were to crash their car and then pricing was set by like adding
20% or whatever. It was just done in a very kind of naive way
so
what I did is I a
You know over many years took this basic process and tried to help lots of companies cigarette how to use it to turn
predictive models into actions
so the starting point
in like actually getting value in a particular model is thinking about what is it you're trying to do and you know
What are the sources of value in that thing you're trying to do?
The levers what are the things you can change? Like? What's the point of a predictive model if you can't do anything about it, right?
Figuring out ways to find what data you you don't have which ones suitable what's available?
then thinking about what approaches to analytics you can then take
and then super important like
well
Can you actually implement, you know those changes and super super important?
how do you actually change things as the environment changes and
You know interestingly a lot of these things areas where there's not very much academic research. There's a little bit and
Some of the papers that have been particularly around maintenance of like how do you decide when your machine learning model is kind of?
Still okay. How do you update it over time? I've had like many many many many citations
But they don't pop up very often because a lot of folks are so focused on the math, you know
And then there's the whole question of like what constraints are in place across this whole thing
So what you'll find in the book is there is a whole appendix which actually goes through every one of these
six things and has a whole list of
Examples written so this is an example of how to like think about
Value and lots of questions that companies and organizations can use to try and think about
You know all of these different pieces of the actual
Puzzle of getting stuff into production and actually into an effective product. We have a question. Sure just a moment
so as I say so do check out this appendix because it actually originally appeared as a blog post and I think except for my
covered 19 posts that I did with Rachel
it's actually the most popular blog post I've ever written it said hundreds of thousands of views and it kind of represents like
20 years of hard one
um insights about like how you actually get value from
Machine learning and practice and what you actually have to ask. So, please check it out because hopefully you'll find it helpful
so when we think about like think
About this for the question of how should people think about the relationship between seasonality and transmissibility of Kovan 19
You kind of need to dig really deeply into the questions about like oh
Not just what what's that? What are those numbers in the data? But what does it really look like, right?
so one of the things in the paper that they show is actual maps right of
temperature and
humidity and ah, right and
you can see like not surprisingly that humidity and
temperature in China
What we would call um order correlated which is to say that places that are close to each other in this case
geographically have similar temperatures and
similar humidities and
so like
This actually puts into the question the a lot the p values
That they have right because you you can't really think of these as a hundred totally separate cities
Because the ones that are close to each other probably have very close behavior
so maybe you should think of them as like a small number of
Sets of cities, you know of kind of larger geographies
so
these are the kinds of things that when you look actually into a model you need to like think about what are the
What are the limitations but then to decide like well, what does that mean? What do I what do I do about that?
You you need to think of it from this kind of utility point of view this kind of end to end
what are the actions I can take order the results point of view not just
Null hypothesis testing. So in this case, for example
There are basically four possible
Key ways. This could end up it could end up that there really is a relationship between
temperature and R or
So that's but the right hand side is or there is no real relationship between temperature and R and
We might act on the assumption that there is a relationship
Or we might act on the assumption that there isn't a relationship and so you kind of want to look at each of these four
possibilities and say like well, what would be the
economic and societal consequences
And you know, there's gonna be a huge difference in
Lives lost and you know economy is crashing and whatever else - you know
for each of these for
The the paper actually, you know has shown if their model is correct
What's the likely our value in March feel like every city in the world and the likely our value in July?
for every city in the world, and so for example, if you look at kind of New England and New York
The prediction here is and also West cut the other the very coast of the west coast. Is that in July
The disease will stop spreading
Now, you know in a that happens if they're right then
That's gonna be a disaster because I think it's very likely in America and also the UK
That people will say Oh
Turns out this disease is not a problem. You know, it didn't really take off at all. The scientists were wrong
people will go back to their previous day-to-day life and
We could see what happened in 1918 flu virus of like the second go around when winter hits
could be much worse than
Than the start right? So like there's these kind of like huge potential
policy impacts depending on whether this is true or false and so - think about it -
Yes. I also just wanted to say that it would be it would be very irresponsible to think. Oh
Summers gonna solve it. We don't need to act now
Just in that this is something growing exponentially and could do a huge huge amount of damage. Yeah. Yes. Okay, it already has done
by the way
if you assume that there will be seasonality and that
Summer will fix things then it couldn't beat you to be apathetic. Now if you assume there's no seasonality and
then there is then you could end up kind of creating a larger level of
Expectation of destruction that actually happens and end up with your population being even more apathetic, you know
So that they're you know being wrong in any direction to be a problem. So
One of the ways we tend to deal with this with with this kind of modeling is we try to think about priors
So our priors are basically things where we you know, rather than just having a null hypothesis
We try and start with a guess as to like, well, what's what's more likely right? So in this case?
If memory serves correctly, I think we know that like flu viruses become inactive at 27 centigrade
We know that like cold the cold
Coronaviruses are seasonal the 1918 the 1918 flu
epidemic was seasonal
In every country and city that's been studied so far. There's been quite a few studies like this
They've always found climate relationships so far
so maybe we'd say well prior belief is that this thing is probably
Seasonal and so they would say well this particular paper adds
Some evidence to that
so like it shows like
how incredibly complex it is to use a
Model in practice for in this case policy discussions but also for like organizational decisions
because you know, there's always
Complexities there's always uncertainties. And so you actually have to think about the
The utility, you know and your best guesses and try to combine everything together as best as you can
okay, so
With all that said
It's still
nice to be able to get our
our models up and running even if you know even just a predictive model is
sometimes useful of its own sometimes it's useful to prototype something and sometimes it's just
It's got to be part of some bigger picture. So rather than try to create some huge into end model here
We thought we would just show you how to
get your
Your PI torch fast AI model
up and running
In his raw a form as possible so that from there you can kind of build on top of it as you like
So to do that
we are going to
Download and curate our own data set and you're going to do the same thing
you've got to train your own model on that data set and then you're going to
Create an application and then you're going to host it know
now
There's lots of ways to create curate an image data set you might have some photos on your own computer
There might be stuff at work you can use
One of the easiest though is just to download stuff of the internet there's lots of services for downloading stuff off the internet
We're going to be using Bing image search here because they're super easy to use
A lot of the other kind of easy to use things require breaking the Terms of Service of websites
so like we're not going to show you how to do that, but
There's lots of examples that do show you how to do that
So you can check them out as well if you if you want to
Being image search is actually pretty great at least at the moment these things change a lot
so keep an eye on our website to see
If we've changed our recommendation
The biggest problem with being image search is that the signup process is a nightmare?
At least at the moment. I feel like one of the hardest parts of this book is just signing up to their damn API
Which requires going through a sure it's called cognitive services as your cognitive services
So we'll make sure that all that information is on the website for you to follow through just how to sign up
So we're going to start from the assumption
That you've already signed up
But you can find it just go being
Being Image Search API and at the moment they give you seven days with a pretty high
Pretty high quota for free and then after that
You can keep using it
as long as you like
But they kind of limit it to like three transactions per second or something, which is plenty you can still do thousands for free
So it's at the moment. It's pretty great. Even for free
So
What will happen is?
When you sign up for being image search or any of these kind of services, they'll give you an API key
So just replace the xxx here with the API key that they give you
Okay, so that's now going to be called key
In fact, let's do it over here
Okay, so you'll put in your key and then there's a
function we've created called search images Bing, which is just a super tiny little
Function as you can see, it's just two lines of code. Just trying to save a little bit of time
Which will take some
Take your API key and some search term and return a list of URLs that match that search term
as you can see for
using
This particular service. You have to install a particular
Package, so we show you how to do that on the site as well
so once you've done so you'll be able to run this and
That will return by default. I think 150
URLs
Okay, so faster Y comes with a download URL function
So he let's just download one of those images just to check and open it up
And so what I did was I searched for grizzly bear and here I have a grizzly bear
So then what I did was I said, okay
Let's try and create a create a model that can recognize grizzly bears versus black bears versus teddy bears
So that way I can find out I could set up some video
Recognition system near our campsite when we're out camping that
Gives me bear warnings
But if it's a teddy bear coming then it doesn't warn me and wake me up because that would not be scary at all
So then I just go through each of those three bear types
Create a directory
With the name of grizzly or black or teddy bear searched being for that particular search term
Along with bear
And download and so download images is a first day I function as well
So after that I can call get image files
Which is a faster a function that will just return recursively all of the image files
Inside this path and you can see it's given me bears black and then lots of numbers
So
one of the things you have to be careful of is that a lot of the stuff you download will turn out to be like
not images at all and will break so you can call verify images to
Check that all of these file names are actual images
And in this case, I didn't have any failed. So there's it's empty. But if you did have some then you would call
path unlink unlink path to unlink is part of the Python standard library and it deletes a file and
Map is something that will call this function
for every element of this collection
this is part of a
special
FASTA a class called L. It's basically
It's kind of a mix between the Python standard library
List class and a numpy array class then we'll be learning more about it later in this course
But it basically tries to make it super easy to do kind of more functional style programming in Python
So in this case, it's going to unlink every thing that's in the failed
List, which is probably what we want
Now because there are all the images that fail to verify. Alright, so we've now got
a path that contains a whole bunch of images and they're classified according to
black grizzly or Teddy based on what folder they're in and
So to create so we're going to create a model and so to create a model. The first thing we need to do is to
Tell fast AI
What kind of data we have and how its structured?
Now in part in lesson 1 of the course, we did that by using what we call a factory method
Which is we just said image data loader start from name and it did it all for us
Those factory methods are fine for
Beginners, but now we're into lesson two. We're not quite beginners anymore
So we're going to show you the super super flexible way to use data in whatever format you like
And it's called the data block API. And so the data block API
Looks like this here's the data block API
You tell first AI what your independent variable is and what your dependent variable is
So what your labels are and what your input data is. So in this case our input data are images
And our labels are categories. So category is going to be either grizzly or black
or teddy
So that's the first thing you tell it now
That's the block's parameter and then you tell it how do you get a list of all of the in this case file names?
Right, and we just saw how to do that because Peters called the function ourselves if the function is called get image files
so we tell it what function to use to get that list of items and
Then you tell it how do you split the data into a validation set and a training set?
And so we're going to use something called a random spitter which just spits it randomly and we're going to point
30% of it into the validation set
we're also going to set the random seed which ensures that every time we run this the validation set will be the same and
Then you say okay. How do you label the data? And this is the name of a function called parent label?
And so that's going to look for each
Item at the name of the parent so this this particular one would become a black bear now
This is like the most common way for
Image datasets to be represented is that they get put the different images get the files get put into folder according to their label
and
Then finally here we've got something called item transforms
we're be learning a lot more about transforms in a moment that these are basically
functions that get applied to each image and so each image is going to be resized to 100 and twenty-eight by
128 square
So we're going to be learning more about datablock api soon
but basically the process is going to be it's going to call whatever is get items which is a list of image files and
Then I'm going to call get X get Y. So in this case, there's no get X but there is a get Y
So it's just parent label and then it's going to call the create method for each of these two things
It's going to create an image and it's going to create a category
Instead. I'm going to call the item transforms, which is resize
And then the next thing it does is it puts it into something called a data loader?
A data loader is something that grabs a few images at a time?
I think by default at 64 and puts them all into a single
It's got a batch. It just grabs 64 images and sticks them all together
And the reason it does that is it then puts them all onto the GPU at once
so it can pass them all to the
Model through the GPU in one go and that's going to let the GPU go much faster as we'll be learning about
And then finally, we don't use any here
We can have something called batch transforms, which we will talk about later and then somewhere in the mineral about here
Conceptually is the splitter which is the thing that splits into the training set and the validation set
So this is a super flexible way to tell fast AI
how to work with your data and so at the end of that
It returns an object of type data loaders. That's why we always call these things deals, right?
So data loaders has a validation and a training
data loader and
a data loader as I just mentioned is something that grabs a batch of a few items at a time and puts it on the
GPU for you
So this is basically the entire code of data loaders
So the details don't matter. I just wanted to point out that like a lot of these
Concepts in fast AI when you actually look at what they are
They're they're incredibly simple
but all things it's literally something that you just pass in a few data loaders to edit store some in an attribute and
Pass and gives you the first one backers train and second one backers valid
So
we can create our
Data loaders by first of all creating the data block and then we call the data loaders passing in our path to create deals and
Then you can call show batch on that
You can call show bachelor pretty much anything in fast AI to see your data and look we've got some Grizzlies
We've got a teddy we've got a grizzly
So you get the idea right
I'm going to look at these different. I'm going to look at data augmentation next week
So I'm going to skip over data-orientation and let's just jump straight into trading your model
So once we've got two yells we can just like in
Lesson one call CNN learner to create a
Resonate we're going to create a smaller resonant this time or isn't it 18?
Again asking for error rate we can then call dot fine-tune again. So you see it's all the same lines of code
we've already seen and
You can see our error rate goes down from nine to one. So we've got one percent error
And after training for about 25 seconds, so you can see you know, we've only got 450 images
we've trained for well less than a minute and we only have let's look at the confusion matrix so we can say I
Want to create a classification interpretation class. I want to look at the confusion matrix and the confusion matrix as you can see
It's something that says for things that are actually black bears
How many are predicted to be black bears?
versus
grizzly bears versus
Teddy bears. So the diagonal are the ones that are all correct. And so it looks like we've got two errors
We've got one grizzly that was predicted be black one black that was predictable grizzly
Super super useful
Method is plot top losses, and that'll actually show me
What my errors actually look like so this one here was predicted to be a grizzly bear but the label was black bear
This one was the one that's predictably a black bear and the label was grizzly bear
These ones here are not actually wrong there
this is predicted to be black and it's actually black but the reason they appear in this is because these are the ones that the
Model was the least confident about
Okay, so we're going to look at the image classifier cleaner next week
Let's focus on how we then get this into production
so
To get it into production
We need to
Export the model. So what exporting the model does is it creates a new file which by default is called export pickle?
Which contains?
The architecture and all of the parameters of the model
so that is now something that you can copy over to a server somewhere and
treat it as a
Predefined program right? So then so the the process of using your trained model
On new data kind of in production is called inference
So here I've created an inference learner by loading that learner back again
All right, and so obviously it doesn't make sense to do it right next to after I've saved it in a notebook
But I'm just showing you how it work. Right? So this is something that you would do on your server in inference and
Remember that once you have trained a model, you can just treat it as a program you can pass inputs to it
So this is now our our program
this is our Bayer predictor so I can now call predict on it and I can pass it an image and
It will tell me
Here is it is?
99.999% sure that this is a grizzly
So I think what we're going to do here is we're going to wrap it up here
And next week we'll finish off by
Creating an actual GUI
for our
bear classifier
We will
show how to
Run it for free on a service call
binder
and
Yeah, and then I think we'll be ready to dive into some of the some of the details of what's going on behind the scenes
Um any questions or anything else before we wrap up Rachel?
Now, okay, great. All right. Thanks everybody. So we
Hopefully, yeah, I think from here on
We've covered
You know, most of the key kind of underlying foundational stuff from a machine-learning point of view that we're going to need to cover
So we'll be able to ready to dive into
Lower-level details of how deep learning works behind the scenes
And I think that'll be starting from next week, so see you then